caredash.com 2018-09-19

# Privacy Policy | CareDash

##  Introduction 

This privacy policy (this "Policy") covers the CareDash Web site www.CareDash.com and any other sites operated under the name ("CareDash" or “the Site”) and any mobile app or other service made available to You (“You”, “Your”, or “Yours”) by CareDash (collectively referred to as the “Services”). 

This Policy describes the types of information that CareDash ("CareDash", " We", "Us" or "Our") gathers from You and the other people who use CareDash (the "Users"), how We may use that information and how You can contact Us regarding this Policy and Your personal information. 

Your Consent. Please read this entire Policy carefully before using CareDash or providing Us with any information. When You access or use CareDash, You consent to the collection, use and disclosure of Your information in accordance with this Policy. By providing personal information to CareDash, all Users fully understand and consent to the collection, use and processing of such information by CareDash or third parties as set forth herein. If You do not agree to the terms of this Policy, You are not authorized to use CareDash. 

You also may give Us permission to access Your information in other services. For example, You may link Your Facebook, Twitter, or Google Plus account to CareDash, which allows Us to obtain information from those accounts. The information We get from those services often depends on Your settings or their privacy policies, so be sure to check what those are. 

Maintaining Your trust is Our top priority, so We adhere to the following principles to protect Your privacy: 

  * We protect Your personal information and will only provide it to third parties: (1) with Your consent; (2) where it is necessary to carry out Your instructions; (3) as reasonably necessary in order to provide Our features and functionality to You; (4) when We reasonably believe it is required by law, subpoena or other legal process; and/or (5) as necessary to enforce Our Terms of Use or to protect the rights, property, or safety of CareDash, Our Members and Visitors, and the public. 
  * We have implemented appropriate security safeguards designed to protect Your information in accordance with industry standards. 

Nufit Media Inc. is the parent company of CareDash. 

##  Information We Collect 

**Registration. To create an account on CareDash, You must provide Us with a** valid email address, and a password and agree to Our Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy, which governs how We treat Your information. You may provide additional information during registration (for example, financial information and information about Your healthcare needs). For healthcare providers, You may provide additional information about Your practice and statements about You (for example, Your personal philosophy of care or Your hobbies and interests). You may provide this information so that We can help You build Your profile and to provide You more customized Services and Offers (for example, insurance offers and suggested healthcare providers). You understand that, by creating an account, We will be able to identify You by Your CareDash profile. We may also ask for Your credit card details if You purchase certain additional services. 

##  Personally Identifiable Information 

CareDash collects personally identifiable information from Our Users at several different points on CareDash, including, without limitation, when Users provide it to Us by (i) contacting Us through email, (ii) registering for use of CareDash or (iii) submitting information through any forms, interactive features or Services available on CareDash. 

Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to, Your name, mailing address, telephone number, email address, credit card information or any other information that might reasonably be used to identify You individually. When other information is directly associated with personally identifiable information, this other information becomes personally identifiable information for purposes of this Policy. We collect this personally identifiable information when You, at any point, manually enter it into any online form available on CareDash or voluntarily submit it to Us in another manner. We may also store Your personally identifiable information in Our systems for use in other ways as described in this Policy. 

In order for You to take full advantage of CareDash You may be asked to voluntarily provide Your personally identifiable information to Us. You may choose not to provide Us with Your personally identifiable information by simply not entering it on CareDash or not otherwise providing it to Us. While You still will have access to CareDash even if You do not provide Us with Your personally identifiable information, You should understand that You will not be able to use certain of the Services or features available through CareDash that require You to enter Your personally identifiable information in order to function. 

**Profile Information.** After You create an account, You may choose to provide additional information on Your CareDash profile, such as information about Your age, gender, date of birth, ethnicity, relationship status, education level, employment status, financial status, interests, and general overall health, including height, weight, physical health, any medical conditions, allergies, lifestyle choices, eating habits, stress levels, sleep health, personal care, health care, family health care, family members. For healthcare providers, You may provide additional information about Your practice, statements about You (for example, Your personal philosophy of care or Your hobbies and interests), and profile pictures or pictures of your facilities (collectively, “Additional Healthcare Provider Information”). Subject to the settings You choose, Your connections may provide recommendations and offers for financial and health services to You. Providing additional information enables You to derive more benefit from Our Services by helping Us identify the types of services and information that would be most helpful to You. It also enables Us to serve You ads and other relevant content on and off of Our Services. Your profile will be entirely private. Your profile information will be available neither to other users browsing the site, nor through search engines. However, Additional Healthcare Provider Information may be made available to other users browsing the site and search engines. 

**Customer Service.** When You contact Our customer support services, We may have to access Your contributions to Our Services and collect the information We need to categorize Your question, respond to it, and, if applicable, investigate any breach of Our Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy. We also use this information to track potential problems and trends and customize Our support responses to better serve You. We do not use this information for advertising. 

**Using Third-Party Services and Visiting Third-Party Sites.** You allow Us to receive information when You use Your account to log in to a third-party website or application. You also allow Us to receive information about Your visits and interaction with the sites and services of Our partners that include Our cookies and similar technologies, unless You opt out. 

We allow third-party companies to collect certain information when you visit our web site or within our email newsletters. These companies may utilize cookies, pixels or other technologies to collect user information (e.g., hashed, de-identified, data, click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit the websites of the Digital Advertising Alliance at [ http://www.aboutads.info/choices. ]()

**Non-Personal Information.** If You do not input or otherwise submit any of Your personally identifiable information, then the information We collect from You is limited. For example, We log Your internet protocol (“IP”) address when You enter, use, and leave the CareDash site in order to help Us diagnose problems with Our server, administer CareDash and track usage statistics. Your IP address may vary each time You visit, or it may be the same, depending on whether You access CareDash through an always-on type of Internet connection (such as cable or DSL), or through a dial-up connection. We match IP addresses to completed User registration forms for validation and error checking purposes. If You reached the Site by clicking on a link or ad from another site, then We may also log that information. This helps Us maximize Our Internet exposure and to understand the interests of Our Users. In general, this information is used to generate overall anonymous reports on Our Users that enable Us to improve the effectiveness of CareDash. 

**Log Files, IP Addresses, and Information About Your Computer and Mobile Device.** When You visit or leave Our Services (whether as a Member or Visitor) by clicking a hyperlink or when You view a third-party site that includes Our plugin or cookies (or similar technology), We automatically receive the URL of the site from which You came or the one to which You are directed. Also, advertisers receive the URL of the page that You are on when You click an ad on or through Our Services. We also receive the IP address of Your computer or the proxy server that You use to access the Internet, Your computer operating system details, Your type of Internet browser, Your mobile device (including Your mobile device identifier provided by Your mobile device operating system), Your mobile operating system (if You are accessing CareDash using a mobile device), and the name of Your internet service provider (“ISP”) or Your mobile carrier. We may also receive location data passed to Us from third-party services or GPS-enabled devices that You have set up, which We use to show You local information on Our mobile applications and for fraud prevention and security purposes. Most mobile devices allow You to prevent real time location data being sent to Us, and of course We will honor Your settings. 

##  Cookie Policy 

We often place a small file known as a "cookie" on Your computer's hard drive. A cookie may contain information that allows Us to track Your path through CareDash and to determine whether You have visited Us before. However, unless You provide Us with personally identifiable information, the cookies will not contain any information that would allow Us to personally identify You. If You do provide personally identifiable information to Us, the cookie is tied to this information so that Our systems will recognize You each time You use CareDash. In that way, We can save Your preferences from visit to visit and present You with a customized version of CareDashYou every time You visit. Our cookies cannot be used to read data from Your hard drive and cannot retrieve information from any other cookies created by other sites. We use cookies in this manner to help Us understand how Users use CareDash, and to help Us to improve CareDash. You may refuse to accept a cookie from Us by following the procedures for rejecting cookies specific to Your web browser. 

We may also use Google Analytics for Display Advertisers to help analyze how Users use the site and remarket the Users with customized Ads. We utilize the User ID feature of Google Analytics to associate Your sessions, and activities in those sessions, across Your devices. You can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers and customized Google Display Network ads by visiting the Ads Preferences Manager. 

If You visit the website of a third party by clicking on an external link on CareDash, they may also use cookies on their website. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This Policy covers the use of cookies by CareDash only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers or other third parties. 

##  User Activity Tracking 

We may employ software technology that enables Us to track certain aspects of a User's visit to CareDash and may allow third parties to deploy such technology through advertisements placed on the Site and other means. This technology helps Us better manage content on CareDash by informing Us what content is effective. The software uses “trackers” to monitor User activity. Trackers are pieces of executable code that are embedded in a web page that track usage activity including, but not limited to, which pages are viewed, when they are viewed, and for how long the pages are viewed. User activity information may be associated with additional information about a User's session, such as a User’s IP address and the type of browser used, and personally identifiable information, if provided by the User. 

If You arrive at the Site by "clicking through" from another website, and You have registered with that other website, then certain information about You that You provided to that other website, such as the terms You were searching that led You to the Site, may be transmitted to Us and We may use it as described in this Policy. You should review the privacy policy of any website from which You reached the Site in order to determine what information was collected by that website and for what purpose(s) You agreed that website could use that information. We may or may not retain that information; if We do, then We may use it in accordance with this Policy. This information may or may not be associated with other User activity data or personally identifiable information. Note that your browser settings may allow you automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to websites that you visit. Like many websites, the Site is not currently configured to respond to Do Not Track signals. 

**Advertising Technologies and Web Beacons.** We target (and measure the performance of) ads to Members, Visitors and others, both on and off of Our Services through a variety of ad networks and ad exchanges, using the following, whether separately or combined: 

  * Advertising technologies on and off of Our Services, like web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies, and mobile identifiers as permitted by mobile platforms; 
  * Member-provided profile and contact information and categories; 
  * Information inferred from a Member‘s profile (for example, names to infer gender); 
  * Your use of Our Services (for example, Your search history, which pages You visit, Your clicking on a CareDash ad, etc.) and log files generated as described in the Log Files Section; 
  * Information from third parties (e.g. advertising partners, publishers and data aggregators) that We use in addition to the information from Our cookies (and similar technologies), Your profile and use of Our Services. 

We may share Your personal information with any third-party advertisers or ad networks for advertising. Also, advertising partners may associate personal information collected by the advertiser directly from You with Our cookies and similar technologies. 

##  How We Use the Information We Collect 

We may use the information (whether or not personally identifiable) that You provide to Us to, among other things: 

  * Make Your use of CareDash more personalized. 
  * Process or complete transactions requested by You. 
  * Contact You regarding administrative issues, such as questions about Your specific request, or otherwise respond to Your comments or requests. 
  * Email information regarding health providers, financial services and other services and offers to You. 
  * Mail information and offers to You. 
  * Make telephone calls and send text messages to You with information and offers. 
  * Provide Your information to third parties to fulfill services You have requested or that may be of interest to You. 
  * Compile anonymous statistical information and analysis. 
  * Provide location based advertising and Services to You. 
  * Provide compiled anonymous information to third parties. 
  * Provide, sell, or rent Your information to third parties for advertising purposes. 
  * Permit You to access certain web-based programs or applications on CareDash. 
  * Help administer and protect the security of CareDash. 
  * Process online purchases or other payment transactions. 

You should be aware that any personal information that is voluntarily posted by You to a public area of CareDash (for example, a physician review, message board or support group) may be viewed and used by other Users. 

**Consent to CareDash Processing Information About You.** By providing personal information to Us when You create or update Your account and profile, You are expressly and voluntarily accepting the terms and conditions of Our Terms of Use and freely accepting and agreeing to Our processing of Your personal information in ways set out by this Privacy Policy. Supplying to Us any information deemed “sensitive” by applicable law is entirely voluntary on Your part. You can withdraw or modify Your consent to Our collection and processing of the information You provide at any time, in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use, by changing Your account settings or Your profile on CareDash or by closing Your CareDash accounts. 

**CareDash Communications.** We may communicate with You through email, notices posted on the CareDash websites or apps, and other means available through the Services. Examples of these communications include: (1) welcome and engagement communications - informing You about how to best use Our Services, new features, updates about other Members You are connected to and their actions, etc.; (2) service communications - these will cover service availability, security, and other issues about the functioning of Our Services; (3) promotional communications - these include both email, and may contain promotional information directly or on behalf of Our partners, including healthcare provider information. These messages will be sent to You based on Your profile information and messaging preferences. You may change Your email and contact preferences at any time by signing into Your account and changing Your CareDash email settings or by sending a written request to CareDash’s physical address, . You can also opt out of promotional messages by sending a request to the [CareDash Help Center.](mailto:support@caredash.com)

Please be aware that You cannot opt out of receiving service messages from Us. 

##  Communications From Us 

We will also communicate with You in response to Your inquiries, to provide the services You request, and to manage Your account. We will contact You either through email, telephone, postal mail or through the Service. 

When it is necessary to do so, We will send You service-related announcements, primarily via email. For example, if Our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, We may send You an email. Generally, You may not opt out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If You do not wish to receive them, You have the option to deactivate Your account by emailing [info@caredash.com.](mailto:%20info@caredash.com)

**Service Development; Customized Experience.** We use information and content that You and other Members provide to Us to conduct research and development for the improvement of Our Services in order to provide You and other Members and Visitors with a better, more intuitive experience and drive membership growth and engagement on Our Services and to help connect individuals to relevant information and offers. 

We also customize Your experience and the experiences of others on Our Services. For example, when You sign in to Your account, We may display content relevant to Your geographic location regarding safety alerts or health service providers in Your area, e.g. We try to show You content, such as news and presentations, that is relevant to You and Your specific needs and concerns. We also may use Your information and content for invitations and communications promoting Our Services or the Services of Our affiliates that are tailored to You. 

**Sharing Information with Affiliates.** We may share Your personal information with Our affiliates (meaning entities controlled by, controlling or under common control with CareDash) as reasonably necessary to provide the Services. You are consenting to this sharing. We may combine information internally across different Services that We offer. 

**Sharing with Third Party Service Providers.**

Please understand that CareDash may contract with third parties to provide various services to CareDash relating to CareDash on an outsourced basis rather than performing the services Ourselves. This includes, but is not limited to, contracting with: (i) an email provider to handle the distribution of email messages to Users of CareDash, (ii) a website hosting provider to host CareDash for Us or (iii) a third party to provide call center services to facilitate communication in connection with Our services. We may also contract with various validation services to confirm contact information You provide. By using CareDash, all Users consent to CareDash providing all information (whether or not personally identifiable) received or collected from those Users to such third party providers for the purpose of enabling the third party provider to provide these outsourced services to Us. In addition, all Users consent to the collection, maintenance, and processing of their information (whether or not personally identifiable) by CareDash and these third party providers. 

**Additional Sharing of Information with Third Parties.**

In addition to the sharing described above, We may disclose any of Your personal information if We have a good faith belief that disclosure is permitted by law or is reasonably necessary to: (1) comply with a legal requirement or process, including, but not limited to, civil and criminal subpoenas, court orders or other compulsory disclosures; (2) enforce this Privacy Policy or Our Terms of Use; (3) respond to claims of a violation of the rights of third parties; (4) respond to Member service inquiries; or (5) protect the rights, property, or safety of CareDash, Our Services, Our Members, Visitors, or the public. 

We may support middleware providers that offer archiving solutions to firms subject to legal and regulatory archiving requirements. 

CareDash may establish subsidiaries or other related companies, or merge with or be acquired by, or sell substantially all of its assets to another company. When that happens, We may disclose to them Your personally identifiable information, in which case We will request them to abide by this Policy. We may also disclose some personally identifiable information to a potential acquirer. 

Third parties (for example, Your email provider) may give You the option to upload certain information in Your contacts stored with Us onto their own service. If You choose to share Your contacts in this way, You will be granting Your third party provider the right to store, access, disclose and use Your these contacts in the ways described in such third party's terms and privacy policy. 

We will share information provided by Users (whether or not personally identifiable) with certain third parties in Our network so that they can contact You with information about the services in which You have expressed interest. In order to provide the Services available to You on this Site, We may also supplement Your information (whether or not personally identifiable) with information from third party sources with whom We have contracted for the purpose of verifying the contact information You have provided. You have the option not to have Your information shared with third parties by not requesting these services. 

We may also share information about Users (whether or not personally identifiable) with third parties so that We can offer You with a broader range of services and information to meet Your needs. If You would prefer not to have Your information shared with third parties, You may opt out by emailing [info@caredash.com.](mailto:%20info@caredash.com)

##  Consent to Telemarketing Calls 

Further, by registering on this Site, You agree that this act constitutes an inquiry and/or application for purposes of telemarketing laws, and notwithstanding that Your telephone and/or cell number may be listed with the federal Do-Not-Call Registry, You expressly opt-in to: (a) receive an offer or service from one or more of Our partners or affiliates; (b) receive future information about products and Services from Us, Our partners, affiliates and other third parties to whom We may provide Your information; (c) permit Us, Our partners, affiliates and other third parties to contact You pursuant to the business relationship We have established using the information You provided to Us for any purpose such as contacting You by email address, phone and/or mobile phone number (including use of automated dialing equipment), text (SMS) message or any means of communication for any purpose that, among other things, Your wireless device may be capable of receiving (e.g. mms, video etc.). You may revoke authorization for Us to contact You by such means at any time (see the Opting Out section below). 

**Surveys & Contests. ** From time-to-time CareDash will request personally identifiable information from Users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the User therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose personally identifiable information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic and location information (such as zip code). Contact information will be shared with the contest or survey sponsors to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of CareDash. Users' personally identifiable information collected through surveys or contests is not shared with third parties who are not agents or service providers, unless We give prior notice and receive Your permission for the sharing. Though We may use an intermediary to conduct these surveys or contests, these intermediaries will not use the Users' personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

**Polls and Surveys.** Polls and surveys may be conducted by Us, Members, or third parties. Some third parties may target advertisements to You on the results page based on Your answers in the poll. We or third parties may follow up with You via email or messages delivered through Our Service. We may use third parties to deliver incentives to You to participate in surveys or polls. If the delivery of incentives requires Your contact information, You may be asked to provide personal information to the third party fulfilling the incentive offer, which will be used only for the purpose of delivering incentives and verifying Your contact information. It is up to You whether You provide this information, or whether You desire to take advantage of an incentive. Your consent to use any personal information for the purposes set forth in the poll or survey will be explicitly requested by the party conducting it. You may opt out of participating in surveys by changing Your settings to stop receiving these inquiries and requests. 

**Search.** You can search for healthcare providers, financial service providers, and other service providers on the CareDash website and the CareDash mobile app. You may also search for information about companies, environmental conditions, and sex offenders in Your area, among other topics. We may use personal information from Our Services, including Member profiles, to inform and refine Our search service. 

**Testimonials and Advertisements Placed Through CareDash Ads.** If You provide any testimonials about Our goods or Services or place advertisements through the CareDash Ads, We may post those testimonials and examples of advertisements You place in connection with Our promotion of these services to third parties. Testimonials and advertisements may include Your name and other personal information that You have provided. 

##  Your Choices and Obligations 

**Rights to Access, Correct, or Delete Your Information, and Closing Your Account.** You have a right to (1) access, modify, correct, or delete Your personal information controlled by CareDash regarding Your profile, (2) change or remove Your content, and (3) close Your account. You can request Your personal information that is not viewable on Your profile or readily accessible to You (for example, Your IP access logs) through CareDash‘s customer service. If You close Your account(s), Your information will generally be promptly removed from the Service. 

Please note: Information You have shared with others (for example, physician reviews, comments on articles) or that others have copied may also remain visible after You have closed Your account or deleted the information from Your own profile. In addition, You may not be able to access, correct, or eliminate any information about You that other Members copied or exported out of Our Services, because this information may not be in Our control. 

**Data Retention.** We retain the personal information You provide while Your account is in existence or as needed to provide You services. We may retain Your personal information even after You have closed Your account if retention is reasonably necessary to comply with Our legal obligations, meet regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce this Privacy Policy and Our User Agreement. We may retain personal information, for a limited period of time, if requested by law enforcement. Our Customer Service may retain information for as long as is necessary to provide support-related reporting and trend analysis only, but We generally delete or de-personalize closed account data consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

**Opting Out; Access to Collected Information.** This Policy describes CareDash’s uses of Your information. If You do not agree to Our uses of Your personally identifiable information as We have described in this Policy, You are not required to provide that information to Us. In addition, if We send emails to You, You may opt out of receiving non-administrative emails from Us simply by responding to the opt-out link provided on all email communications from CareDash. You may review, update and delete any personal information that You have provided to Us through this Site by emailing [info@caredash.com.](mailto:%20info@caredash.com)

##  Important Information 

**Minimum Age.** As described in the Terms of Use, persons must be of Minimum Age to use CareDash. 

##  CareDash Policy Regarding Children Under the Age of 18 

CareDash complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). COPPA requires that website operators never knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18 without prior verifiable parental consent. The Site is not intended for children under the age of 18, and CareDash does not knowingly collect or use personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18. If We discover personal data from a child under the age of 18, We will eliminate that data. 

You are not permitted to use CareDash if You are under the age of 18. By using CareDash, You agree to provide Us with accurate information concerning Your age or identity if We request it. You also agree not to assist children under the age of 18 in accessing CareDash or to attempt to contact children under 18 through CareDash. 

**California’s Shine the Light Law.** California Civil Code Section 1798.83, known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits Our customers who are California residents to request and obtain from Us a list of what personal information (if any) We disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the names and addresses of those third parties. Requests may be made only once a year and are free of charge. Under Section 1798.83, We currently do not share any personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. 

**Security.** CareDash will take reasonable measures to secure the personally identifiable information Users provide to Us. However, CareDash cannot guaranty the security of any information You submit to Us and You do so at Your own risk. All personally identifiable information is protected by password and accessible only to authorized CareDash personnel. However, there is a possibility that Internet transmissions containing a User's personally identifiable information may be intercepted by others. There is no way for Us to ensure the privacy of User information before it arrives at CareDash or after it leaves CareDash. 

**Changes to Policy.** If We make material changes to this Policy, We will post a notice on the home page regarding the amended Policy, so that You are aware of what personally identifiable information We collect, how We use it, and under what circumstances, if any, We disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time, so please review CareDash frequently for any changes. Amendments to this Policy will be posted on CareDash and will be effective when posted. You will be deemed to have been made aware of, will be subject to, and will be deemed to have accepted, the changes to any amended or revised Policy by Your continued use of Our services or CareDash. 

##  Contact Us 

If You have any questions about this Policy please contact Us via email at [info@caredash.com.](mailto:%20info@caredash.com)

  * To opt out and unsubscribe from email communications, send an email to [info@caredash.com](mailto:%20info@caredash.com) with "unsubscribe" in the subject line. 
  * To cancel or correct Your personal information: send an email with Your Email Address and the notice "My User Information" in the subject line to [info@caredash.com.](mailto:%20info@caredash.com)
  * To express or ask questions regarding privacy concerns: send an email to [info@caredash.com](mailto:%20info@caredash.com) or send Us mail to:  614 Massachusetts Ave   
Suite 400   
Cambridge, MA 02139
